Praise the Lord!
Yes.
What a God we have to worship!
What a Son we have to praise!
What a future lies before us!
Greet your neighbour. Say, "Good Morning!"
Greet the next person beside you. Say, "Good Morning!"
Viewers all over the world, Good Morning!
Hallelujah!
You may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to see joyful faces.
Camera man, can you give us shots of joyful faces.
We want to see joyful faces.
Hallelujah!
Yes.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to believe that you have done your exercise this morning.
You have done your exercise this morning?
You know, exercise does not only mean when you go to the gym
and you are on your treadmill running or jogging.
Or maybe you are on your bike cycling.
You can also take a 10 to 30 minutes walk in a day.
And whilst you are walking, smile.
Tell your neighbour, "Make sure you smile".
What do I mean?
I mean, when you take a 10 to 30 minutes walk a day,
always remember the prophetic word of our father in the Lord, Prophet T.B. Joshua.
He said: "Oh Holy Spirit, take more of me, give me more of You".
I mean, whilst you are doing this 10 to 30 minutes walk,
let this be what you say in your heart.
Let this be a joyful heart.
That is what I mean by when you walk, make sure you smile.
If you have not done your exercise this morning,
you may probably find yourself restless or sleeping.
Sometimes, you can find yourself going to the toilet five to six times whilst the service is going on.
Why? - Because food and water are not rightfully positioned in your body.
So tell your neighbour once again with a smile,
"Have a joyful face".
With a smile in your heart, say to your neighbour,
"My neighbour, I know that my case is settled today".
Are you sure?
[Yes!]
Yes.
If indeed you know that your case is settled, then who shall separate us from the love of Christ?
[Nobody!]
If indeed you know that your case is settled in Heaven,
who then shall separate us from the love of Christ?
Shall persecution?
[No!]
Shall tribulation, affliction, poverty?
Absolutely nothing!
Let someone say, "Absolutely nothing can separate us from the love of Christ!"
Hallelujah!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brethren, when you look around the world today, you will agree with me
that our generation is facing uncommon challenges
and uncommon challenges demand uncommon faith to be saved.
When you look at what is happening around you,
when you look at what is happening around the world in general,
you will agree with me that our generation is facing uncommon challenges
and uncommon challenges demand uncommon faith to be saved.
It is important for us to know that in life, we do have days, weeks, months and years
that come with enormous challenges.
They are inevitable.
It is the time and season when God wants us to learn the important and crucial lessons of life;
as such, they are unchangeable events because they are predestined to prepare us,
to strengthen our desire for Christ.
When they come, how best do you handle them?
When they come, as Christians, how best do you handle those periods?
Majority of us are spiritually blind, spiritually dull - dull in understanding,
with the unseen realm absolutely closed to our spiritual vision.
We can only see the outward effects of satan's actions but we are blind to our spiritual course.
We can only see something happening but we don't know the cause.
God oftentimes uses foolish things to prepare us,
to strengthen our desire and determination for Him,
to stop us awhile and rearrange us for the future.
Whatever difficulties that you are facing,
whatever challenges that you may be passing through,
be assured that it is not your challenges that make you fall
but your response and your reaction to them.
It is not your challenges that make you fall or fail in life
While some of us yield to pressure and make wrong decisions,
others face the same challenges but make the right decisions.
Always remember that broken focus is the real reason why men fail today.
Whatever challenges that you are going through,
it is not your challenges that make you fall but your response and your reaction to them.
While some of us yield to pressure and make wrong decisions.
Others faced the same pressures, the same tests and trials but made the right decision.
Always remember that broken focus is the reason why people fail.
Regardless of your situation, choose today to let the One who created you assist you in all you do.
I don't know the situation you are going through but I know Jesus knows.
Whatever might be your challenges, brethren,
choose today to let the One who created you assist you.
Do not allow your bad experience to limit you.
Do not allow your bad experience to wipe you out.
Why don't you turn your scars into stars?
Why don't you turn your mess into a message?
Why don't you turn your tests into a testimony?
Tell your neighbour, "No matter my situation, I will turn my scars into stars".
I will turn my scars into stars.
A Christian is known by his ability to face situations and circumstances.
I believe I'm talking to God's people.
I believe if you're not, before the end of this message, you will be one, in Jesus' name.
Viewers all over the world, a Christian is known by his ability to face situations and circumstances.
Those who see beyond their challenges, those who see beyond their situations,
do not despair in the face of their seeming setbacks.
But today we oftentimes run away from the very thing that brings strength into our lives.
Today we oftentimes dodge situations that bring strength into our lives.
Tell your neighbour, "Turn your scars into stars".
Let's quickly open our Bible to the Book of Romans and that will be our proof text.
The Book of Romans - let's take it from chapter 8.
The Book of Romans - after the Book of Acts.
Just before the Book of 1 Corinthians.
The Book of Romans, chapter 8.
Let's take our reading from verse 1.
Are you there?
SCRIPTURE REFERENCE
Romans 8:1
"There is therefore now no condemnation to those who are in Christ Jesus,
who do not walk according to the flesh, but according to the Spirit."
Who do not walk according to what is seen but according to what is unseen.
Who do not walk according to senses but according to faith.
I take that verse 1 again.
"There is therefore now no condemnation to those who are in Christ Jesus,
who do not walk according to the flesh, but according to the Spirit."
For the law of the Spirit of life in Christ Jesus has made me free from the law of sin and death."
Let's go to verse 31.
"What then shall we say to these things?"
Are you there?
"If God is for us, who can be against us?
He who did not spare His own Son, but delivered Him up for us all,
how shall He not with Him also freely give us all things?
Who shall bring a charge against God's elect? It is God who justifies.
Who is he who condemns? It is Christ who died, and furthermore is also risen,
who is even at the right hand of God, who also makes intercession for us."
Verse 35.
"Who shall separate us from the love of Christ?
Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or peril, or sword?
As it is written: 'For Your sake we are killed all day long.
We are accounted as sheep for the slaughter.'
Yet in all these things we are more than conquerors through Him who loved us.
For I am persuaded that neither death nor life, nor angels nor principalities nor powers,
nor things present nor things to come,
nor height nor depth, nor any other created thing,
shall be able to separate us from the love of God which is in Christ Jesus our Lord."
Let someone say, "Amen!"
Tell your neighbour, "Turn your scars into stars".
No matter the situation you may be facing, turn them into stars.
Throughout history, the lives of the heroes of faith have proved
that we are created to live for God's design and not by default.
When you read your Bible from Genesis to Revelation, you will agree with me
that the lives of the heroes of faith have proved that we are to live
for God's design and not by default.
Remember there are two sides to a coin, just as there are two dimensions to life.
And as the saying goes, "No wounds, no pearls" -
there can be no promotion without a test.
I believe we all want promotion but you must be ready to go through some little challenges.
There can be no success without failure.
Brethren, there can be no promotion without a test.
There can be no strengths without weaknesses.
There can be no good health without sickness
and there can be no victory without war.
The war I am talking about is not a physical combat but a spiritual warfare
where only a God-focused, I mean a serious-minded person, will be victorious.
Only a God-focused, serious-minded person will be victorious.
If you believe you are going to walk on a red carpet to get there, you are wrong.
Brethren, if you believe you are going to walk on a red carpet -
nothing poking you, nothing distracting you - then you are wrong.
Those unpleasant situations that you are going through right now
are part of your journey to success.
Those foolish things are part of your journey to success.
Today, many have changed the course of their lives
through their inability to see beyond their immediate setbacks, their immediate stops.
Many marriages have collapsed,
many relationships today have collapsed
because of people's inability to see beyond their temporary setbacks, temporary challenges.
Many have changed businesses because they could not see beyond their setbacks.
Ask any successful businessperson, any successful couple,
they will tell you stories of their setbacks and comebacks.
Ask any successful person, any successful couple,
I want you to know that the beginner is not the owner but the finisher.
Finishers are those who always exercise great faith under great trials and persecution.
Tell your neighbour.
Whatever situation you may be facing, remember the Book of 1 Corinthians 10:13.
It says no temptation has seized us except what is common to man.
Sometimes, today when we are faced with situations
that look like temporary stops, temporary setbacks,
we easily make wrong steps, we easily make wrong judgements,
we easily make negative reactions,
we easily make negative choices
instead of examining our lives in the light of God's Word.
Sometimes we love to move faster than our shadow
and that is why most of the time we make mistakes;
we regret some of the decisions that we make in life.
Sometimes when we are faced with situations that look like temporary setbacks,
we easily overreact.
We easily behave negatively instead of examining our lives in the light of God's Word.
We want to move faster than our shadow
and that is why we oftentimes regret some of the decisions that we took.
As Christians, our challenges force us to look deep enough,
to explore possibilities, to draw closer to God,
to dream of other ways that we might have ignored when tests and trials come.
There is always a lesson to be learnt.
Many don't want to learn those lessons; we want to move ahead of our future,
ahead of our shadow.
That is why the Bible tells us in the Book of 1 Corinthians
that no temptation has seized us except what is common to man, for the Lord is faithful.
He will not allow you to be tempted beyond what you can bear.
And when you are tempted, He will also provide a way out for us so that we can overcome.
Remember Jesus will not run the race for us,
but He promised to strengthen our minds against storms, thorns, snakes and scorpions
on our road to success.
You ask Peter in the Book of Luke 5 and he will tell you
that what we see as failure is not failure at all, from eternity's perspective,
from God's point of view.
What we see as rejection, what we see as setback
is not from eternity's perspective, from God's point of view.
We serve a God who oftentimes uses foolish things to confound the wise.
The unpleasant situation you are going through right now is so foolish.
God oftentimes uses foolish things to confound the wise.
Brethren, to the wise, disappointment is a foolish thing
but God oftentimes uses disappointment to preserve us for redemption.
Poverty, to the wise, is a foolish thing
but God oftentimes uses poverty to prevent us from death.
Rejection, to the wise, is a foolish thing
but God oftentimes uses rejection to prepare us for a new level in life.
Tell your neighbour, "My situation may look like a setback,
my situation may look like a stop,
it may look like a delay but it is not".
In any case, delay is not a denial.
Delay is not a denial.
When you are faced with a situation that looks like a setback, stay focused.
Maintain a balanced frame of mind,
dig deep and fight it through.
It takes faith to realise that our situation is a mere stopping interval,
a break between two events.
Therefore, when your situation gets hotter, you are getting closer to your breakthrough.
Let someone say, "I'm getting closer".
"I have no doubt I'm getting closer."
"I have no doubt I'm getting closer to my breakthrough, to my healing, to my deliverance,
to all of God's blessings in my life."
If you believe that, put your hands together for our Lord Jesus!
There is no doubt we are getting closer to our breakthrough.
We need experience to maintain greatness.
What is your situation?
Is it an inability to get a job in spite of your qualifications?
Is it lateness in marriage in spite of your prayers and fasting?
Is it hatred or rejection in spite of your hard work?
Is it health challenges that seem not to be yielding to your prayer?
Always remember that events that seem ordinary may have extraordinary effects in the spirit,
much of which is hidden from the ordinary mind.
Always remember when you face situations and you don't know what is happening,
always remember that events that seem ordinary may have extraordinary effects in the spirit,
much of which is hidden from the ordinary mind.
But it takes a reflective mind
to realise that behind our situation lies the promise of God for our lives.
It takes faith.
In the Book of Daniel 6 - we all know the story of Daniel -
when the decree was published, the Bible says that
Daniel knew that nothing beautiful, nothing giant and huge could be created
without a measure of toil, a measure of pain.
He knew if the human sympathy of King Darius had saved him from the sad part of his life
when he was sent to the lion's den,
the glorious part that followed would have been lost.
In the face of life's threat,
the Bible says that he maintained a balanced frame of mind
and he turned his scars into stars.
Brethren, if human sympathy could save you, you would have been saved a long time ago.
If human sympathy - money, wealth, position, popularity, fame - could save you,
you would have been saved a long time ago.
Sometimes when we are faced with situations, we begin to seek alternatives,
we begin to seek human sympathy to save us, to help us.
We begin to seek shortcuts, alternatives in an attempt to escape from reality.
It does not take long to realise
that shortcuts and alternatives have their own way of disappointing one.
If you cry to human beings for help, you will receive human sympathy
but that will not solve your problem.
It is only Jesus Christ, the Author and Finisher of our faith, that can solve it -
the One who has no beginning and He has no end.
Brethren, greatness begins with wounds.
When you accept your adversity,
the Bible says when we endure every pain, we will learn what we need to know
and our grief will turn to gain.
Tell your neighbour, "No matter my situation, I know He will turn my scars into stars".
Finally, brethren, let the Book of 1 Corinthians 9:24-25 encourage you.
When you run, run in such a way as to obtain the prize.
All of us who are falling made a decision
but all of us who have not fallen faced similar temptations
but made a different decision.
At one point in our lives we all feel like giving up.
We all feel at one point in our lives when we are faced with situations, we all feel like giving up.
You might be asking yourself, "Why do I have to go through trials?"
"Why do I have to go through all this pain, shame, embarrassment,
rejection, name-calling, persecution, poverty?"
Yes.
It is because Somebody wants to turn turn your test into a testimony.
I tell you: Somebody wants to turn turn your test into a testimony.
It is because Somebody wants to turn your poverty into prosperity, in the name of Jesus Christ!
It is because Somebody wants to turn your frustration, your failure into fruitfulness,
in the name of Jesus Christ!
Who knows what would have become of you if those temporary setbacks,
if those temporary stops, had not come at intervals?
Who knows where we would be today?
But with deep reflection, you will know that there is a purpose of God behind your situations.
Brethren, this is encouragement to the timid soul like me.
Are you doing today what you ought to have done earlier in life?
Brethren, are you facing today what you ought to have done earlier in life?
With proper reflection, you will know that your case is not that of failure
but a refusal to do what you ought to have done earlier in life.
Never forget that patience, perseverance, endurance, humility pay off at last.
Perseverance, endurance, obedience, faithfulness pay off at last.
Do not allow your circumstances to rob you, to limit you.
Let the One who created you assist you today
and turn your scars into stars.
If you make the Word of God your rule and the grace of God your principle,
victory is yours, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Victory is yours, in the Blood of Jesus Christ!
May the Lord bless His Word in the midst of our heart, in Jesus' name.
Let someone say, "Thank You, Jesus,
for turning my scars into stars, no matter my situation.
Thank You for turning my scars into stars, in Jesus' name!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 18/04/2019
RV Robert Begier 19/04/2019